<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Review on Andi Altendorfer</title>
    <link>https://iboard.github.io/tags/review/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Review on Andi Altendorfer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Andi Altendorfer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iboard.github.io/tags/review/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Big Move</title>
      <link>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2026-02-24-infomaniak-ksuite/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2026-02-24-infomaniak-ksuite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Moving away from the dominant Big Tech ecosystem often feels like a daunting task—one that usually involves a complex weekend of &amp;ldquo;digital surgery.&amp;rdquo; However, I recently made the switch to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.infomaniak.com/en/ksuite/myksuite&#34;&gt;kSuite&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; the Swiss-based collaborative solution from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://infomaniak.com&#34;&gt;Infomaniak&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, and the experience was surprisingly smooth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for a digital home that values privacy, independence, and cost-effectiveness without the &amp;ldquo;Silicon Valley&amp;rdquo; strings attached, here is why kSuite should be on your radar.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omarchy on a 2017 MacBook Pro: A Developer&#39;s Perspective</title>
      <link>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2026-01-18-omarchy-macbook-pro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2026-01-18-omarchy-macbook-pro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-omarchy-experience-on-a-2017-macbook-pro&#34;&gt;My Omarchy Experience on a 2017 MacBook Pro&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not every day that a new operating system truly impresses me, especially when running on older hardware. However, my recent experience with Omarchy on my trusty 2017 MacBook Pro has been overwhelmingly positive. This setup has, hands down, provided the best development environment I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered to date.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, this particular MacBook Pro has been a workhorse. While it&amp;rsquo;s still a capable machine, newer macOS versions have sometimes felt a bit sluggish, and the overall experience wasn&amp;rsquo;t as snappy as it once was. Enter Omarchy. From the moment I installed it, the system felt revitalized. The interface is clean, intuitive, and remarkably responsive, breathing new life into the hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The White Screen App</title>
      <link>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-11-15-white-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-11-15-white-screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-iphones-transformation-with-the-white-screen-app&#34;&gt;My iPhone&amp;rsquo;s Transformation with the &amp;ldquo;White Screen&amp;rdquo; App&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;div style=&#34;float: left; margin-top: 0.75em; margin-right: 1em; width: 6em;&#34;&gt;&#xA;  &lt;img alt=&#34;White Screeen Thumbnail&#34; src=&#34;https://iboard.github.io/images/2025-11-14-whitescreen.png&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In our hyper-connected world, the smartphone has become an extension of ourselves. It’s our communication hub, our source of entertainment, and our primary tool for productivity. However, this constant connectivity comes at a price. The endless stream of notifications, the alluring glow of app icons, and the siren call of social media can easily pull us into a vortex of distraction, leaving us feeling drained and unproductive. I, for one, have often found myself mindlessly scrolling through feeds, checking for updates, and losing precious time to the digital abyss. This is a story about how I reclaimed my focus and boosted my productivity with a surprisingly simple solution: the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://apps.apple.com/us/app/white-screen-minimal-launcher/id6737041451&#34;&gt;White Screen&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; app.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Review of the Remarkable Paper Pro</title>
      <link>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-09-19-remarkable-paper-pro-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-09-19-remarkable-paper-pro-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the &lt;a href=&#34;https://remarkable.com&#34;&gt;Remarkable Paper Pro&lt;/a&gt; since 2021, and it has become an indispensable part of my daily routine. As someone who loves the feel of writing on paper but needs the convenience of digital notes, the Remarkable has been a game-changer.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://iboard.github.io/images/remarkable_paper_pro.png&#34; alt=&#34;Remarkable Paper Pro&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-writing-experience&#34;&gt;The Writing Experience&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The first thing that struck me about the Remarkable is how natural it feels to write on. The textured surface of the screen and the pressure-sensitive stylus create an experience that is remarkably close to writing on paper. There&amp;rsquo;s no lag, and the &amp;ldquo;ink&amp;rdquo; flows smoothly from the stylus. It&amp;rsquo;s a joy to use for everything from jotting down quick notes to long-form writing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
