<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Webdev on Andi Altendorfer</title>
    <link>https://iboard.github.io/tags/webdev/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Webdev on Andi Altendorfer</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Andi Altendorfer</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://iboard.github.io/tags/webdev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Never Look Back: A Phoenix Rises from Rails&#39; Ashes</title>
      <link>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-11-07-never-look-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-11-07-never-look-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-the-end-of-a-journey-the-start-of-another&#34;&gt;Introduction: The End of a Journey, The Start of Another&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Every software developer has a path, a winding road of languages, frameworks, and philosophies that shapes their craft. My own journey has taken me through the structured landscapes of Pascal, the raw power of C++, and the wild, chaotic frontier of early PHP web development. For a long time, I was a journeyman, picking up tools as I needed them, solving problems, and moving on. Then came the era of frameworks, promising order, productivity, and a &amp;ldquo;right way&amp;rdquo; to build things. And for a significant part of the web&amp;rsquo;s history, the undisputed king of that era was Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Directories with Nginx Basic Auth</title>
      <link>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-10-14-nginx-basic-auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://iboard.github.io/posts/2025-10-14-nginx-basic-auth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;protecting-your-web-content&#34;&gt;Protecting Your Web Content&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you have content on your website that you don&amp;rsquo;t want to be publicly accessible. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a private section for family and friends, or a staging area for a new project, Nginx&amp;rsquo;s basic authentication is a simple and effective way to password-protect parts of your site.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk through how to protect a directory called &lt;code&gt;/private&lt;/code&gt; and everything inside it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-creating-the-password-file&#34;&gt;1. Creating the Password File&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;First, we need to create a &lt;code&gt;.htpasswd&lt;/code&gt; file that will store our username and password. The password needs to be encrypted. We can use the &lt;code&gt;htpasswd&lt;/code&gt; command-line tool for this. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have it, you can usually install it with &lt;code&gt;apache2-utils&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
